Guide to the Lawrence Tibbett Collection ARS.0041
Archive of Recorded Sound
Lawrence Tibbett Collection
1929-1945
ARS.0041
Tibbett, Richard M.
2.8 linear feet, 3 audio disc storage boxes for 12" sound discs; 1 small box with tape reel; 1 document storage box for miscellaneous documents
Archive of Recorded Sound, Stanford University Libraries Stanford, California 94305-3076
The collection contains primarily sound recordings of performances of Lawrence Tibbett from recording sessions that occurred between 1929 and 1945. Some of the recordings are 12" vinyl 33 1/3 rpm microgroove discs, but most are 78 rpm shellac discs and 12" instantaneous discs. A few 10" 78 rpm single-sided test pressings, and 1 7" tape reel are also included. Written materials in the collection consist of a set of of 13 index cards with handwritten listings of the contents of tape reels in Tibbett's personal collection (tape reels not included in this collection), photocopies of published articles by Tibbett, and typed inventories of the collection which were prepared by the donor.
Box 1-5
Conditions Governing Access note
Collection is open for research. Listening appointments may require 24 hours notice. Contact the Archive Operations Manager.
Biographical/Historical note
Born in Bakersfield, California (USA) on November 16, 1896, baritone Lawrence Tibbett began his career as an actor as well as a singer in performances of light operas and also in churches. Tibbett's teachers were Joseph Dupuy and Basil Ruysdael in Los Angeles and Frank La Forge and Ignaz Zitomirsky in New York. Tibbett's study in New York led to his Metropolitan Opera debut in the role of Lewicki in Boris Godunov in 1923. Following shortly after his Met debut he sang the role of Valentin in Faust. In 1925 Tibbett became an overnight sensation in the role of Ford in Falstaff, and he later assumed the title role. He eventually sang many leading Italian, French, German and American roles at the Met and remained a principal with the company for 27 seasons. He sang in the premières of Deems Taylor's The King's Henchman (1927) and Peter Ibbetson (1931), Louis Gruenberg's The Emperor Jones (1933), Howard Hanson's Merry Mount (1934) and John Laurence Seymour's In the Pasha's Garden (1935). The first Metropolitan Opera performances of Jonny spielt auf, Peter Grimes, Richard Hageman's Caponsacchi, as well as Simon Boccanegra and Khovanshchina also included Tibbett in the cast. His last appearance at the Met occurred in 1950 as Ivan in Khovanshchina. In 1936, along with violinist Jascha Heifetz, he founded the American Guild of Musical Artists, and served as its president for 17 years. Tibbett appeared in major opera houses around the U.S. and the world, including San Francisco, Chicago, Paris, London, Vienna and Prague, and at Covent Garden he created the title role in Eugene Goossens's Don Juan de Mañara (1937). In addition to performing on stage, Tibbett also sang frequently in radio performances during the early years of his career. Partly as a result of his striking good looks, as well as his dark, agile voice, Tibbett had significant success in film roles and light opera. He also appeared in Broadway stage productions, and his last Broadway role was in the musical comedy Fanny in 1956. His recordings for Victor sold in the millions. Among his best recordings are those of Verdi's Otello, in which he sang the role of Iago, and the live recording of his 1935 performance of La Traviata at the Met with Rosa Ponselle. Tibbett died in New York, on July 15, 1960.
Scope and Contents note
The Lawrence Tibbett Collection was assembled and donated by his son, Richard M. Tibbett. The recordings in the collection are primarily privately issued 12" sound discs, both 78 rpm and 33 1/3 rpm. The collection also includes 10" single-sided discs recorded for the Victor Company, 1 7" tape reel, and written materials consisting of a set of 13 index cards with handwritten notes in pencil, photocopies of pages from published articles by Tibbett, and photocopies of two typed inventory lists of the collection prepared by the donor.
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged by material type in five boxes as follows: (1) Vinyl and aluminum sound discs, arranged in chronological order by recording session date with undated materials at the end; (2-3) Shellac and instantaneous sound discs, arranged in chronological order by recording session date with undated materials at the end of Box 3; (4) 1 reel-to-reel tape; (5) 13 handwritten index cards with information about content of audio tapes in Tibbett's personal collection, none of which are included in this collection; typed and photocopied documents.
Indexing Terms
Arlen, Harold, 1905-1986; Froman, Jane, 1907-1980; Goodman, Al, 1890-1972; Goossens, Eugene, 1893-1962; Green, Bud, 1897-1981; Gruenberg, Louis, 1884-1964; Hanson, Howard, 1896-1981; Hupfeld, Herman, 1894-1951; Jaffe, Moe, 1901-1972; Lange, Johnny, 1905-2006; Margetson, E. J.; Mercer, Johnny, 1909-1976; Metropolitan Opera (New York, N.Y.). Chorus.; Metropolitan Opera (New York, N.Y.). Orchestra.; Newman, Alfred, 1901-1970; Porter, Cole, 1891-1964; Romberg, Sigmund, 1887-1951; Seymour, John Laurence; Taylor, Deems, 1885-1966; Templeton, Alec, 1910-1963; Tibbett, Lawrence, 1896-1960; Weiskopf, Carroll; Operas--19th century; Operas--20th century; Operas--Excerpts; Motion picture music--Excerpts; Vocal duets with orchestra; Popular music--1931-1940; Popular music--1941-1950; National songs--United States; Radio program excerpts
Container List
- Vinyl and Aluminum Sound Discs: Recording Sessions 1929-1939: Songs, Arias, Complete Operas, 1929-1935; 42.0 items (Box 1)
  General note
  Sound recordings on 12" discs of various songs, arias, and complete operas, recorded between 1929 and 1939. Some discs are 78 rpm aluminum discs; others are 33 1/3 rpm reissues on vinyl discs.
  - Lawrence Tibbett, baritone., 1929-1936; 2.0 LPs; Vinyl sound disc (2 copies), 33 1/3 rpm microgroove LP. (Box 1, Discs 1-2)
    Scope and Contents note
    Performed by Lawrence Tibbett, and recorded between 1929 and 1936. CONTENTS: Side 1. Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Meistersinger von Nürnberg. Wahn! Wahn! Überall Wahn! English -- Flotow, Friedrich von, 1812-1883. Martha. Lasst mich euch fragen. English [Porter song] -- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Traviata. Di Provenza il mar -- Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Serse. Ombra mai fù -- Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880. Contes d'Hoffmann. Scintille, diamant -- Giordano, Umberto, 1867-1948. Andrea Chénier. Nemico della patria. Side 2: Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Falstaff. È sogno? [Ford's monologue] -- Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893. Roméo et Juliette. Ballade de la reine Mab -- Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924. Trittico. Tabarro. Scorri, fiume eterno -- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Trovatore. Balen del suo sorriso -- Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924. Tosca. Mi dicon venal -- Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912. Hérodiade. Vision fugitive [on disc: Vision fuggitive (Thomas)] -- Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893. Faust. Vous qui faites l'endormie [Mephistofele's serenade].
    1 vinyl sound disc: 33 1/3 rpm, microgroove (2 copies).
    Golden Age of Opera: EJS-110 A, EJS-110B
  - Hanson, Howard, 1896-1981. Merry Mount. World premiere recording:, 02-10-1934; 4.0 LPs; 2 12" vinyl sound discs, 33 1/3 rpm, microgroove (2 copies of each). (Box 1, Discs 3-6)
    Recorded Feb. 10, 1934. Performed by Lawrence Tibbett, Edward Johnson, Gladys Swarthout, et al.; Metropolitan Opera Orchestra and Chorus, Tullio Serafin, conductor.
    Act I, Parts 1-2; Act II, Part 1: Golden Age of Opera: EJS-134A, EJS-134B (2 copies)
    Act II, Part 2; Acts III-IV: Golden Age of Opera: EJS-134C, EJS-134D (2 copies)
    Johnson, Edward, 1878-1959; Serafin, Tullio, 1878-1968; Swarthout, Gladys, 1900-1969
  - Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919. Pagliacci. Prologo. (incomplete), 1934; 1.0 78 rpm disc; 12" aluminum disc, with handwritten markings in center of disc. Label is detached and stored in accompanying envelope. (Box 1, Disc 7)
    Performed by Lawrence Tibbett and recorded in a 1934 Firestone Concert.
    Radio Recording Studio (New York): L.T. 66e
  - Charles, Ernest, 1895-1984: Someone [from the motion picture Metropolitan], 1935; 1.0 78 rpm disc; 12" vinyl 78 rpm single-sided sound disc. (Box 1, Disc 8)
    Sung by Lawrence Tibbett and Carol Weiskopf, [with orchestra] conducted by Alfred Newman. Recorded in 1935.
    Columbia (Private Recording): 1378-27, Take S-96, Prod. 1300, "Metrolpolitan" (engraved on disc)
  - [Harold Arlen:] Last night, duet [from the motion picture Metropolitan], 1935; 4.0 78 rpm discs; 1 12" vinyl 78 rpm single-sided sound disc (4 copies). Printed on labels of copies 1-2: "A limited pressing of 36 private recordings for my friends" (Box 1, Discs 9-12)
    [Performed by Lawrence Tibbett, baritone; Carroll Weiskopf, vocalist], Alfred Newman, conductor. Recorded in 1935.
    Columbia: 1378-41 (label); additional information engraved on disc, partially covered by label (2 copies).
    Columbia/United Artists Corporation: P S111, Wax no. 1378-33, Prod. 1300, "Metropolitan" (engraved on 3rd copy).
    Plain white label [Columbia?]: S118 S119 SP120, Wax no. 1373, Prod. 1300 "Metropolitan" (engraved on 4th copy).
  - Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919. Pagliacci. Prologo. [from the motion picture Metropolitan], 1935; 4.0 78 rpm discs; 12" 78 rpm vinyl sound disc (4 copies). Copies 1-2: Printed on label: "A limited pressing of 36 private recordings for my friends." Copy 2 is private pressing no. 35. Copy 3: White label with "United Artists Corporation" "Pressed by Columbia" and playing time grid printed on label. Copy 4: Plain white label with "78" stamped in red and crossed out in blue ink, "33" handwritten in blue ink above "78". (Box 1, Discs 13-16)
    [Performed by Lawrence Tibbett with orchestra], Alfred Newman, conductor. Recorded in 1935.
    Columbia: 1378-7 (label); Track S50, D7 Wax no. 1378-7, Prod. 1300, "Metropolitan" (engraved on discs, copies 1-3)
    Plain white label: 1329 (label); Track P S50, Wax no. 1329, Prod. 1300 "Metropolitan" (engraved on copy 4)
  - Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919. Pagliacci. Vesti la giubba [from the motion picture Metropolitan], 1935; 4.0 78 rpm discs; 12" vinyl 78 rpm single-sided sound disc (4 copies). Copies 1-3: Printed on label: "A limited pressing of 36 private recordings for my friends" Copy 4: White label with "United Artists Corporation" "Pressed by Columbia" and playing time grid printed on label. (Box 1, Discs 17-20)
    Performed by Lawrence Tibbett, Alfred Newman, conductor. Recorded in 1935.
    Columbia: 1378-10 (label); D10 Wax no. 1378-10, Prod. 1300, "Metropolitan" (engraved on all discs)
  - Speaks, Oley, 1874-1948. On the road to Mandalay [from the motion picture Metropolitan], 1935; 2.0 78 rpm discs; 12" vinyl 78 rpm single-sided sound disc (2 copies). Copy 1: Printed on label: "A limited pressing of 36 private recordings for my friends" Copy 2: Plain white label with title and number stamped in red. Title on copy 2: "Road to Mandalay" (Box 1, Discs 21-22)
    Performed by Lawrence Tibbett [with orchestra], Alfred Newman, conductor. Recorded in 1935.
    Copy 1: Columbia: 1378-29 (label); Take S-98 Wax no. 1378-29, Prod. 1300, "Metropolitan" (engraved on disc)
    Copy 2: [Plain label]: 1360 (label); Take S-98, Wax no. 1360, Prod. 1300 "Metropolitan" (engraved on disc)
  - Glory road (from the motion picture Metropolitan), 1935; 1.0 78 rpm disc; 12" vinyl 78 rpm single-sided sound disc. Printed on label: "A limited pressing of 36 private recordings for my friends" (Box 1, Disc 23)
    Columbia: 1378-23 (label); Take S-92 Wax no. 1378-23, Prod. 1300, "Metropolitan" (engraved on disc)
    Handwritten on reverse side: 4' 45"
  - Bizet, Georges, 1838-1875. Carmen. Chanson du toréador [from the motion picture Metropolitan], 1935; 3.0 78 rpm discs; 12" vinyl 78 rpm single-sided sound disc (3 copies). Copies 1-2: Printed on label: "A limited pressing of 36 private recordings for my friends" Copy 3: White label with "United Artists Corporation" "Pressed by Columbia" and playing time grid printed on label. (Box 1, Discs 24-26)
    Columbia: 1378-2 (label); [Take] S-18 D2 Wax no. 1378-2, Prod. 1300, "Metropolitan" (engraved on all discs)
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Simon Boccanegra., 02-16-1935; 4.0 78 rpm disc(s); 2 12" vinyl sound discs, 33 1/3 rpm, microgroove (2 copies of each disc). (Box 1, Discs 27-30)
    Performed by Lawrence Tibbett, Elisabeth Rethberg, Giovanni Martinelli, et al., Metropolitan Opera Chorus and Orchestra, Ettore Panizza, conductor.
    The Golden Age of Opera: EJS-177A, EJS-177B (2 copies); EJS-177C, EJS-177D (2 copies)
    Martinelli, Giovanni, 1885-1969; Panizza, Ettore; Rethberg, Elisabeth, 1894-1976
  - Packard program: part one., 02-26-1935; 2.0 78 rpm disc(s); 12" aluminum electrical transcription disc. Various handwritten markings on disc (2 copies). (Box 1, Discs 31-32)
    Side 1: Lawrence Tibbett announces "Sweet grass range" Side 2: Lawrence Tibbett sings "Sweet grass range"
    Electro-Vox Air Chek disc for NBC:KFI
    Copy 1: Handwritten timing on disc: 3' 43"
  - Packard program: part two., 02-26-1935; 1.0 78 rpm disc; 12" aluminum electrical transcription disc. Various handwritten markings on disc. Recorded Feb. 26, 1935. (Box 1, Disc 33)
    Warren, Elinor Remick, 1900-1991: Sweet grass range. Sung by Lawrence Tibbett.
    Electro-Vox Air Chek, for NBC:KFI.
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Tannhäuser., 01-18-1936; 3.0 LPs; 3 12" vinyl sound discs, 33 1/3 rpm, microgroove. Reissue of recording made Jan. 18, 1936. (Box 1, Discs 34-36)
    Performed by Kirsten Flagstad, Lauritz Melchior, Lawrence Tibbett, et al., Orchestra and Chorus of the Metropolitan Opera Association, Arthur Bodanzky, conductor.
    The Golden Age of Opera: EJS-109A, EJS-109B, EJS-109C, EJS-109D, EJS-109E, EJS-109F
    Bodanzky, Artur, 1877-1939; Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Melchior, Lauritz
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Rigoletto., 03-11-1939; 4.0 LPs; 2 12" vinyl sound discs, 33 1/3 rpm microgroove (2 copies of each disc). (Box 1, Discs 37-40)
    Performed by Lily Pons, Jan Kiepura, Lawrence Tibbett, et al., Metropolitan Opera Chorus and Orchestra, Gennaro Papi, conductor. Recorded Mar. 11, 1939.
    The Golden Age of opera: EJS-131A - EJS-131B (2 copies); EJS-131C - EJS-131D (2 copies)
  - Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868. Barbiere di Siviglia. Largo al factotum., 1.0 78 rpm disc; 12" aluminum 78 rpm sound disc. Title handwritten on label in blue ink on side 1. Handwritten on side 1: 4 Handwritten on side 2: 5 (Box 1, Disc 41)
    [Performed by Lawrence Tibbett]
    Speak-O-Phone Recording Studio
  - The Best of the Kingston Trio, 1.0 LP; 12" vinyl 33 1/3 rpm LP. (Box 1, Disc 42)
    Contents: Tom Dooley - The Tijuana jail -- Scotch and soda -- Bad man's blunder -- Raspberries, strawberries -- Everglades -- M.T.A. -- The merry minuet -- Where have all the flowers gone -- Billy goat hill -- Take her out of pity -- A worried man.
    Capitol Records: The Star Line: T-1705 (T1-1705, T2-1705); T-1-1705-G-6 (matrix), T-2-1705-DL 2 (matrix)
    Note in donor's inventory states: "Probably not part of LT's collection"
- Shellac and Instantaneous Recordings: 1937-1945, 47 78 rpm discs (Box 2)
  - Hanson, Howard, 1896-1981. Merry Mount. Excerpt., 01-19-1934; 1.0 78 rpm disc; 12" shellac 78 rpm single-sided sound disc. (Box 2, Disc 1)
    Performer: [Lawrence] Tibbett.
    RCA Domestic Red Seal: CS-81086-1/19/33 (engraved on disc) Handwritten on disc: "1934, not 33" [also] "Error-1934!"
    Handwritten on label: 2A
    Handwritten on disc: Unpub. Take
  - Hallelujah rhythm., 10-19-1936; 1.0 78 rpm disc; 12" 78 rpm shellac single-sided sound disc. Plain white label with title information handwritten in ink. RCA Victor logo on reverse side of disc. (Box 2, Disc 2)
    Performed by Lawrence Tibbett. Recorded Oct. 19, 1936.
    RCA Victor: 02175-1A (no. handwritten in pencil on label)
  - De hallelujah rhythm., 2.0 78 rpm disc(s); 12" shellac single-sided sound disc (2 copies). Commercial label with title and performer information in typescript, and manufacturer logo on reverse side. (Box 2, Discs 3-4)
    Performed by Lawrence Tibbett, with orchestra.
    Allied Phonograph and Record Co.
    Possibly copies of Victor CS-02175-1
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Rigoletto. Cortigiani, vil razza dannata., 10-19-1936; 1.0 78 rpm disc; 12" 78 rpm shellac sound disc, single-sided test pressing (Box 2, Disc 5)
    Plain white label: 02173-3 (handwritten in pencil); title and date handwritten in ink.
  - Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904. Symphonies, no. 9, op. 95, E minor. Largo. Selections; arr., 10-19-1936; 1.0 78 rpm disc; 12" shellac 78 rpm single-sided sound disc. Plain white label with title, composer and other information handwritten in pencil. RCA Victor logo on reverse side of disc. (Box 2, Disc 6)
    Title on disc: Goin' home.
    [Performed by Lawrence Tibbett]. Recorded Oct. 19, 1936.
    "5 min., 10 sec." (handwritten on label)
    RCA Victor: 02176-1 (handwritten matrix no. on label)
  - Schwartz, Arthur, 1900-1984: Amigo (from the motion picture Under your spell), [1936?]; 2.0 78 rpm discs; 12" shellac 78 rpm single-sided sound disc. Plain white label with title and composer information handwritten in pencil. RCA Victor logo on reverse side of disc (2 copies) (Box 2, Discs 7-8)
    RCA Victor: 97791-1 (matrix)
  - Star-spangled banner (Song), 02-15-1937; 1.0 78 rpm disc; 12" instantaneous 78 rpm single-sided sound disc. (Box 2, Disc 9)
    Performed by Lawrence Tibbett. Recorded Feb. 15, 1937.
    Handwritten timing on disc: 2:00.
    Transcriptions Incorporated.
  - Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Semele. Where'er you walk., 01-04-1940; 1.0 78 rpm disc; 12" shellac 78 rpm single-sided sound disc. Plain white label with title and matrix no. handwritten in pencil or ink. RCA Victor logo on reverse side of disc. (Box 2, Disc 10)
    [Performed by Lawrence Tibbett.] Recorded Jan. 4, 1940.
    RCA Victor: 046065-2
  - Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Theodora. Defend her, Heav'n!, 01-04-1940; 2.0 78 rpm discs; 12" shellac 78 rpm single-sided sound disc. Plain white label with title and matrix no. handwritten in pencil. RCA Victor logo on reverse side of disc (2 copies) (Box 2, Discs 11-12)
    RCA Victor: 046066-2 (copy 1); 046066-3 (copy 2)
  - Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Allmacht (Song), 01-04-1940; 1.0 78 rpm disc; 12" shellac 78 rpm single-sided sound disc. Plain white label with title and matrix no. handwritten in pencil. RCA Victor logo on reverse side of disc. Handwritten in pencil: "Defective cannot be repaired. Thumps." (Box 2, Disc 13)
    Title on disc: The omnipotence.
    Performed by Lawrence Tibbett. Recorded Jan. 4, 1940.
    RCA Victor: 046070-1
  - Ford Sunday Evening Hour: Damrosch, Walter, 1862-1950. Danny Deever -- Youmans, Vincent, 1898-1946. Through the years. Through the years., 01-07-1940; 1.0 78 rpm disc; 12" vinyl 78 rpm sound disc. Commercial label with title and performer information in typescript. (Box 2, Disc 14)
    Performed by Lawrence Tibbett.
    Champion Recording Corp. for radio station WABC, Jan. 7, 1940, 9:00 p.m.
  - Accentuate the positive (music by Harold Arlen), 02-03-1945; 1.0 78 rpm disc; 12" instantaneous 78 rpm transcription disc. Commercial label with title in typescript, other information handwritten in ink. (Box 2, Disc 15)
    Performed by Lawrence Tibbett and the Hit Paraders Chorus.
    Empire Transcription: trial recording.
    Recorded Feb. 3, 1945.
  - [Your Hit Parade] WABC, 9:00-9:45 p.m.:, 02-03-1945; 2.0 78 rpm disc(s); 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs: 1 double-sided disc, 1 single-sided disc. Commercial labels with all information in typescript. (Box 2, Discs 16-17)
    Hallelujah! -- Chloe ["Cloe" is written on label] -- Don't fence me in (music by Cole Porter)
    Rockhill Recording.
  - [Hit Parade] CBS Line, 9:00-9:30 p.m.:, 02-17-1945; 3.0 78 rpm discs; 3 12" instantaneous 78 rpm single-sided sound discs. Commercial label, with all information in typescript. (Box 2, Discs 18-20)
    Porter, Cole, 1891-1964. Gay divorce. Night and day -- Youmans, Vincent, 1898-1946. Through the years. Drums in my heart -- Accentuate the positive (music by Harold Arlen)
    Universal Recording Co.
  - [Hit Parade] WABC, 9:00-9:45 p.m.:, 02-17-1945; 2.0 78 rpm discs; 2 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs: 1 double-sided disc, 1 single-sided disc. (Box 2, Discs 21-22)
    Rockhill Recording Company.
  - [Your Hit Parade] CBS, 12:00-12:45 a.m.:, 02-24-1945; 2.0 78 rpm discs; 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs: 1 double-sided disc, label on side 2 missing; one single-sided disc. Commercial labels with all information in typescript. (Box 2, Discs 23-24)
    Rodgers, Richard, 1902-1979. Oklahoma! Oh, what a beautiful mornin' -- [Tierney, Harry, 1890-1965. Rio Rita. Rangers' song] (NB: Label missing; information from donor's inventory) -- Accentuate the positive (musc by Harold Arlen)
  - [Your Hit Parade] WABC, 9:00-9:45 p.m.:, 03-03-1945; 2.0 78 rpm discs; 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs. 1 disc is double-sided, labels detached and stored separately; 1 disc is single-sided, label detached and stored separately. Commercial labels with all information in typescript. (Box 2, Discs 25-26)
    Separated Materials note
    3 labels detached from discs stored in separate envelopes with discs.
    Don't fence me in (music by Cole Porter) -- Accentuate the positive (music by Harold Arlen) -- Army Air Corps song
    Rockhill Recordings.
  - Texaco Star Theater, WABC, 9:30-10:00 p.m.:, 03-04-1945; 2.0 78 rpm discs; 2 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs. (Box 2, Discs 27-28)
    Side 1 performed by Lawrence Tibbett. Sides 2 and 4 performed by Lawrence Tibbett, with Alec Templeton. Side 3 performed by Lawrence Tibbett and Jane Froman.
    Side 1: Léhar, Franz, 1870-1948. Land des Lächelns. Dein ist mein ganzes Herz. English [Yours is my heart alone] -- Side 2: Bizet, Georges, 1838-1875. Carmen. Chanson du toréador [2' 10"] -- Side 3: Romberg, Sigmund, 1887-1951. New moon. Wanting you -- Side 4: [Unidentified work]
  - [Hit Parade] CBS Line, 9:00-9:45 p.m.:, 03-10-1945; 2.0 78 rpm discs; 2 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs: 1 double-sided disc, 1 single-sided disc. (Box 2, Discs 29-30)
    Romberg, Sigmund, 1887-1951. New moon. Lover, come back to me -- Friml, Rudolf, 1879-1972. Vagabond king. Song of the vagabonds -- Accentuate the positive (music by Harold Arlen)
  - Texaco Star Theater, WABC, 9:30-10:00 p.m.:, 03-11-1945; 4.0 78 rpm discs; 4 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs: 3 double-sided discs and 1 single-sided disc. (Box 2, Discs 31-34)
    Side 1: Kern, Jerome, 1885-1945. Sally. Look for the silver lining
    Side 2: Stothart, Herbert, 1885-1949. Rogue song [from the motion picture The rogue song] (performed by Lawrence Tibbett)
    Side 3: He's home for a little while. (performed by Jane Froman)
    Side 4: Intro. to Goin' home. (performed by Alec Templeton)
    Side 5: Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904. Symphonies, no. 9, op. 95, E minor. Largo. Selections; arr. (Goin' home). (performed by Lawrence Tibbett, with chorus)
    Side 6: Gershwin, George, 1898-1937. Rhapsody in blue. (performed by Alec Templeton, piano)
    Side 7: Gershwin, George, 1898-1937. Porgy and Bess. Bess, you is my woman. (performed by Lawrence Tibbett and Jane Froman)
  - [Your Hit Parade] WABC, 9:00-9:45 p.m.:, 03-17-1945; 2.0 78 rpm discs; 2 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs: 1 double-sided disc and 1 single-sided disc. (Box 2, Discs 35-36)
    Youmans, Vincent, 1898-1946. Great day. Great day -- More and more -- Accentuate the positive (music by Harold Arlen)
  - [Texaco] Star Theater, WABC, 9:30-10:00 p.m.:, 03-18-1945; 4.0 78 rpm discs; 4 12" glass-based instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs. Disc 1 is cracked. (Box 2, Discs 37-40)